http://ornithology.com/privacy-policy/

Search for:
Skip to content
This Privacy Policy governs the manner in which Ornithology.com collects, uses, maintains and discloses information collected from users (each, a “User”) of the http://ornithology.com website (“Site”). This privacy policy applies to the Site and all products and services offered by Ornithology.com. To be clear, Ornithology.com is really not interested in collecting information from users, but we put this disclaimer here just to cover our bases.
Personal identification information
We may collect personal identification information from Users in a variety of ways, including, but not limited to, when Users visit our site, subscribe to the newsletter, fill out a form, and in connection with other activities, services, features or resources we make available on our Site. Users may be asked for, as appropriate, name, email address, mailing address, phone number. We will collect personal identification information from Users only if they voluntarily submit such information to us. Users can always refuse to supply personally identification information, except that it may prevent them from engaging in certain Site related activities.
Non-personal identification information
We may collect non-personal identification information about Users whenever they interact with our Site. Non-personal identification information may include the browser name, the type of computer and technical information about Users means of connection to our Site, such as the operating system and the Internet service providers utilized and other similar information.
Web browser cookies
Our Site may use “cookies” to enhance User experience. User’s web browser places cookies on their hard drive for record-keeping purposes and sometimes to track information about them. User may choose to set their web browser to refuse cookies, or to alert you when cookies are being sent. If they do so, note that some parts of the Site may not function properly.
How we use collected information
Ornithology.com may collect and use Users personal information for the following purposes:
– To improve customer service
Information you provide helps us respond to your customer service requests and support needs more efficiently.
– To personalize user experience
We may use information in the aggregate to understand how our Users as a group use the services and resources provided on our Site.
– To improve our Site
We may use feedback you provide to improve our products and services.
– To run a promotion, contest, survey or other Site feature
To send Users information they agreed to receive about topics we think will be of interest to them.
– To send periodic emails
We may use the email address to respond to their inquiries, questions, and/or other requests. If User decides to opt-in to our mailing list, they will receive emails that may include company news, updates, related product or service information, etc. If at any time the User would like to unsubscribe from receiving future emails, they may do so by contacting us via our Site.
How we protect your information
We adopt appropriate data collection, storage and processing practices and security measures to protect against unauthorized access, alteration, disclosure or destruction of your personal information, username, password, transaction information and data stored on our Site.
Sharing your personal information
We do not sell, trade, or rent Users personal identification information to others. We may share generic aggregated demographic information not linked to any personal identification information regarding visitors and users with our business partners, trusted affiliates and advertisers for the purposes outlined above.
Changes to this privacy policy
Ornithology.com has the discretion to update this privacy policy at any time. When we do, we will revise the updated date at the bottom of this page. We encourage Users to frequently check this page for any changes to stay informed about how we are helping to protect the personal information we collect. You acknowledge and agree that it is your responsibility to review this privacy policy periodically and become aware of modifications.
Your acceptance of these terms
By using this Site, you signify your acceptance of this policy. If you do not agree to this policy, please do not use our Site. Your continued use of the Site following the posting of changes to this policy will be deemed your acceptance of those changes.
Contacting us
If you have any questions about this Privacy Policy, the practices of this site, or your dealings with this site, please contact us at:
Ornithology.com
4798 Songbird Lane
Chico, CA 95973. USA.
Contact
This document was last updated on November 19, 2014.
Search for:
Subscribe to Blog via Email
Enter your email address to subscribe to Ornithology.com and receive notifications of new posts by email.
Join 312 other subscribers
Email Address
Subscribe
About Us Accurate and complete information about wild birds from a professional ornithologist. The Ornithologist at Ornithology.com has written ten books, among them: Amazing Birds, Birds of New England,  Bird Finder, Pacific Coast Bird Finder, Latin for Bird Lovers, Beaks, Bones, and Bird Songs, and The Art of the Bird : Ornithological History Through Forty Artists.
Quick Links Home
Birdwatching
Blog
Conservation
Facts
Teacher Resources
Contact
Other Resources Free Bird IdentificationApp for Apple or Android
Contact Information Ornithology.com
4798 Songbird Lane
Chico, CA 95973. USA.
Click here to send us a
message or question about wild birds.
Recent CommentsPaula Monroe on Bread or NotDr. Roger Lederer on Blogging About BirdsDr. Roger Lederer on The Hearing of BirdsDan on Blogging About BirdsRay Leiter on The Hearing of BirdsArchives Archives
Select Month
December 2020  (1)
November 2020  (5)
October 2020  (4)
September 2020  (4)
August 2020  (4)
July 2020  (4)
June 2020  (5)
May 2020  (4)
April 2020  (4)
March 2020  (5)
February 2020  (4)
January 2020  (3)
December 2019  (5)
November 2019  (4)
October 2019  (5)
September 2019  (1)
August 2019  (4)
July 2019  (5)
June 2019  (4)
May 2019  (5)
April 2019  (4)
March 2019  (4)
February 2019  (4)
January 2019  (5)
December 2018  (4)
November 2018  (7)
October 2018  (3)
September 2018  (4)
August 2018  (5)
July 2018  (5)
June 2018  (3)
May 2018  (4)
April 2018  (4)
March 2018  (7)
February 2018  (3)
January 2018  (2)
December 2017  (7)
November 2017  (5)
October 2017  (1)
September 2017  (1)
August 2017  (4)
July 2017  (4)
June 2017  (1)
May 2017  (2)
April 2017  (1)
March 2017  (3)
February 2017  (2)
January 2017  (2)
December 2016  (1)
November 2016  (3)
October 2016  (4)
September 2016  (2)
August 2016  (2)
July 2016  (1)
March 2016  (9)
February 2016  (9)
January 2016  (4)
December 2015  (3)
November 2015  (9)
October 2015  (9)
September 2015  (9)
August 2015  (5)
July 2015  (3)
June 2015  (6)
May 2015  (2)
April 2015  (2)
March 2015  (4)
February 2015  (2)
January 2015  (3)
Leave a Reply Cancel reply
Your email address will not be published. Required fields are marked *Comment Name *
Email *
Website
Save my name, email, and website in this browser for the next time I comment.
Notify me of new posts by email.
This site uses Akismet to reduce spam. Learn how your comment data is processed.
